# **Katie Antlitz**

## Software Developer

E-mail ksantlitz@gmail.com

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/in/katinthecode

**WWW** www.katinthecode.com

A creative and curious full stack developer with over nine years of experience developing and maintaining many different projects. I've worked through the full development cycle from use cases and functional requirements to the end product. I continue to learn and experiment with new technologies.

### **Experience**

10-2020 - present

### **Software Developer**

Utilidata

Utilidata is a company that creates real-time software that helps to optimize the settings of the electric grid.

- · Assisted in developing a new product that will work with smart devices
- · Assisted in creating Python APIs designed to read information from the devices
- Created Java Spring API that allows users to change settings
- Testing and reviewing my teammates' code

#### 07-2019 - 10-2020

# **Research and Development Developer**

Performance Livestock Analytics

PLA is a technology company that provides farm management tools in the livestock industry.

- I work on PLA's research and development team
- Currently creating a way to send data from an rfid tag reader to insert into system using MQTT, Python, GoLang, and Node.js
- · Created a new API to access and update animal tag information
- Helped to create new Animal Health project using Swift and MySQL for iOS
- Work with IOT devices to manage livestock
- Work with Android developmen to create an app that scans rfid tags and updates animal information using Bluetooth devices
- · Research ways to connect and use new technologies

### 11-2016 - 04-2019

### **Senior Software Developer**

**ICOMM** 

ICOMM is a company that handles telecommunications for clients, including mobile devices, voice systems, help desk support, and expense management. I worked on a small team of developers to create external and internal applications, console applications for data loading, reports detailing client expenses and usage, and worked with many different vendors to set up delivery of invoices through EDI.

- Worked on ETL console application with a webpage that allows the internal users to import different formats of
  documentation including comma delimited, XLS, and XML formats and map each column to a database table
  and column specified by the user. The system then saves this information and automatically starts importing
  the files as they are uploaded.
- Worked on development of Ordering Portals tailored to the needs of different external clients using C#.NET,
   .NET Framework, WebForms, HTML5, Bootstrap, and SQL
- Created ETL to automate ServiceNow data importing and SSRS reports to display employee statistics
- Added features to legacy code including the ability to request automated invoices, dynamically build Excel spreadsheet reports for telecommunication usage.

- Maintained legacy desktop and Windows applications using VB.NET, .NET Framework, WebForms/WinForms,
   HTML, and SQL stored procedures
- Created automated reports using SSRS, Excel Spreadsheets, and dynamically (using C#) created Excel
   Spreadsheets from stored procedures I created for external and internal client use
- Maintained production and test environments using Azure and internal Windows 2012 servers
- Introduced best practices to improve software documentation, team planning, release processes and customization of applications based on client needs
- · Mentored junior and senior level developers

#### 08-2016 - 11-2016

#### Amazon

ICQA Software Developer

I worked as the Joliet fulfillment center's only software developer to create a website and reports that assisted management in to better innovate process improvements, create and track critical action items, and resolve issues.

- Created the MDW2 Fulfillment Center's internal ICQA website using Ruby on Rails in a Linux environment using AWS and Oracle databases
- Worked with senior level management to create and improve reports in Ruby to better support their needs

#### 11-2014 - 08-2016

### **Internal Applications Developer**

CSG Government Solutions

CSG Government Solutions provides consultation to help state governments modernize critical program enterprises. I was part of a two person team that worked on supporting internal applications. These applications included the internal website, learning management system, Android applications and console applications. I also created reports as needed and worked to fix any bugs that came up.

- Created new Android app that contained and maintained the library of legal documentation needed by the consultants, including feedback and usage reports in order to monitor the most used documents
- Created and lead the development of a SCORM compliant Learning Management System using C#.NET, .NET,
   Webforms, HTML5, JavaScript, Outlook REST APIs, and WebEx REST APIs
- · Created SSRS reports using stored procedures that I created
- Redesigned internal SharePoint website using CSS, HTML, and JavaScript
- · Maintained and added new features to legacy code

#### 01-2012 - 11-2014

### **Software Developer**

Applied Systems, Epic Accounting

Applied Systems is an insurance software company. I worked on the accounting team for Applied's Epic software. I started as a junior developer working on small fixes and moving my way into a more midlevel development role working on different features. I worked through three full project lifecycles of Epic.

- Worked on a project to rewrite receipts, disbursement, and voucher functionality to include the ability to override
  completed receipts by administrators and keep track of previous changes using VB.NET, .NET, WinForms, and
  SQL on the distributed system Epic
- Worked on a project to batch process transactions
- Lead a feature project to improve check printing for disbursements
- Maintained legacy code for Epic
- Worked directly with large clients to create new features
- · Worked on test agile team before Applied fully converted
- Mentored junior developers

### **Education**

### DePaul University, MS in Computer Science

I have been working on my MS in CS specializing in software development. I have one course to complete before graduating in the spring.

09-2009 - 06-2012

# **DeVry University, BS in Computer Information Systems**

- Graduated Cum Laude
- Member of Alpha Sigma Lambda National Honors Society
- Dean's List

# **Volunteer Work**

09-2014 - present

### **Troy School District**

Volunteer

- Read to classes
- Chaperone field trips
- Assist choir director before performances

11-2009 - 01-2011

# **Family Outreach Program**

Volunteer

Sorted and entered accounting data into Quickbooks

Unloaded trucks

Preparing food boxes

# **Personal Hobbies**

Virtual Reality and gaming

Working on redesigning my website, www.katinthecode.com using HTML5, PHP, MySQL

Cozy mysteries

Technology